Jeffery Shivers

Software Engineer

126 BORDER STREET BOSTON, MA 02128 (409) 679-3765 JEFFERYSHIVERS@GMAIL.COM JEFFERYSHIVERS.COM

Skills

I am a full stack software engineer with experience primarily in Java and Node using tools like Dropwizard, ExpressJS, React, Typescript, Pulsar, and gRPC. I love working on complex integrations across systems and planning clean architectures on new and scaling projects.

Experience

APRIL 2018 - PRESENT

Toast Inc, Boston - Software Engineer (10.2018 - present), App Developer (4 - 10.2018)

- As a full stack developer, I've helped architect and build a new domain of services that sits between
 customers and internal users. Heavily focused on clean/extensible applications to support many integrations
 with other tools and services (both internal and 3rd party).
- As the first member of my current project, I've had the opportunity to experience a product scaling from the ground up and also gain a strong understanding of and empathy for stakeholders' needs.
- Helped develop a culture of pair programming and learning opportunities for newer engineers on the team.
- Helped train new teammates and improve the onboarding process.
- Interviewed candidates for roles from SE1 to principal positions.
- **Tools**: Java, Node, Dropwizard, ExpressJS, React, Datadog, JUnit, Jest, Gradle, AWS (SecretsManager, KMS, DynamoDB, CloudWatch, etc.), PostgreSQL, Salesforce, CSS3, git.

JANUARY 2018 - APRIL 2018

precisioneffect, Boston - UI Architect

- Full stack developer for a small team focused on fast development of mostly web applications.
- Mostly focused on deploying UI-heavy progressive web apps, and building better infrastructure around projects as the number of live applications grew.
- Tools: Node, React, ExpressJS, AWS (Lex, DynamoDB, Lambda), Digital Ocean, CSS3, git.

JUNE 2017 - JULY 2017

IDEO, Cambridge - Fellow, Software Engineer

- Developed a series of rapid prototypes as POC's for the Open Music API specification.
- Tools: Node, JQuery, ExpressJS, Firebase, Codeship, CSS3, git.

APRIL 2016 - AUGUST 2016

GNU + **Google Summer of Code, Boston** - Intern, Software Engineer

- Worked on GNU LilyPond music notation software developing a library of extensions called scholarLY for creating academic annotations and other complex tweaks to musical scores.
- Tools: Scheme, LilyPond, TeX, git.

Education

JULY 2017 - NOVEMBER 2017

Launch Academy, Boston - Software Development Bootcamp

- TDD and CI/CD-focused course using React, Redux, Enzyme, Jasmine, Rails, PostgreSQL, Codeship, and git.
- Capstone: nombook.com, a recipe editor/manager built using React/DraftJS, Rails and Postgres.

AUGUST 2014 - MAY 2016

Tufts University, Medford MA - Master of Arts, Music (Composition)

- **GPA**: 4.0.
- Teaching Assistant for Intro to Music Theory (2 semesters) and History of Jazz
- Thesis: eisfabrik: a composition for sextet https://dl.tufts.edu/pdfviewer/2j62sh30v/6969zc38q

AUGUST 2010 - MAY 2014

Lamar University, Beaumont TX - Bachelor of Music (Composition)

• **GPA**: 3.64, cum laude.

Awards

2017 Harvard Summer Music Institute Fellowship - Harvard U. and Earle Brown Music Foundation.
2016 Award for Outstanding Academic Scholarship (Master's Level) - Tufts U. (top award in the graduate school).
2016 Graduate Research Competition - Tufts U. (provided funding to travel and give a lecture on my work at Fabra i Coats in Barcelona).

Projects

https;//github.com/jefferyshivers/paper

Paper - a Java API / library for composing and rendering documents, with implementations for HTML (using the W₃C document implementation) and a PDF renderer (using the Flying Saucer library).

https://github.com/jefferyshivers/boop

Boop - a messaging service with a core Java service using gRPC and Pulsar, and example gRPC client wrappers in Java and Javascript. This project is meant to exemplify how one might blend gRPC and Pulsar to create a simple messaging service. Includes unit tests with JUnit 5 and Mockito.

https://github.com/jefferyshivers/latex-js

latex-js - a Node library (written in Typescript) for creating LaTeX source code in a functional way. I wanted to explore how a dynamic programming context could complement the robust TeX typesetting system. Includes unit tests written with Mocha.

Additional Interests

I love cooking, running, and all things related to music. I studied music in college and grad school, and spent a couple years traveling the U.S. and Europe for several artist residencies. I found my way into software development through my love of music, starting with Google Summer of Code in 2016 where I got to work for my favorite music notation software, GNU LilyPond. I also occasionally write articles at https://medium.com/@jefferyshivers.